# Benjamin D. Killeen

Ph.D. Student, Johns Hopkins University
Department of Computer Science
3400 N Charles St
Baltimore, MD 21218, USA
killeen@jhu.edu

benjamindkil	lleen.com - 🤻	arcade.cs.jhu.edu	- :0:	cirl.lcsr.jhu.edu	
Benjamin D.	Killeen - 📵	0000-0003-2511-7929	- 0	benjamindkilleen - 🛩 @bdkilleer	า

### Summary

A Ph.D. Student at Johns Hopkins University, I am a member of the Advanced Robotics and Computationally Augmented Environments (ARCADE) research group and the Computational Interaction and Robotics Laboratory (CIRL). My research interests include computer vision, reinforcement learning, and domain generalization, with a focus on applications in robotic manipulation, medical imaging, and clinician-centered surgical robotics.

#### Education

Ph.D., Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.

08/2019 - present
With Mathias Unberath and Gregory D. Hager.

**B.A., Computer Science with Honors, Physics Minor**, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 09/2015 - 06/2019 Thesis: Starting from Scratch: Deep Learning for Novel Scientific Image Analysis With Gordon Kindlmann.

#### Research Experience

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2020 - present With Mathias Unberath, Gregory D. Hager.

**Research Assistant**, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Johns Hopkins University, 08/2019 - 06/2020 Baltimore, MD, USA.

With Gregory D. Hager, Mathias Unberath, and Russel Taylor. Recipient: LCSR Fellowship for Outstanding Incoming Ph.D. Students.

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 03/2018 - 08/2019 With Gordon Kindlmann.

## Professional Experience

Computer Vision / Al Intern, Applied Research, Intuitive Surgical Inc., Sunnyvale, CA, USA. 06/2020 - 07/2020 With Omid Mohareri.

Software Development Intern, Cognitive Computing, Epic Systems, Verona, WI, USA.06/2018 - 08/2018Research Intern, IBM Research - Almaden, San Jose, CA, USA.06/2017 - 08/2017With Geoffrey Burr.06/2017 - 08/2017

## Selected Honors

Best Graduate Project Award, Computer Integrated Surgical Systems and Technology course, Johns05/2020Hopkins University, USA.COVID-19 Dataset Award, Kaggle.04/2020

For our county-level dataset in [M-1].

Intuitive Surgical Best Project Award, Deep Learning course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.

12/2019
Project: Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks.

With Michael Peven, Shaoyan Pan, and Matthew Pittman.

## Publications

My publication list is also available on Google Scholar. \*Asterisk indicates equal contribution.

Peer-reviewed Journal Articles

A. Hundt, **B. D. Killeen**, H. Kwon, C. Paxton, GD Hager. "Good Robot!": Efficient Reinforcement

Learning for Multi-Step Visual Tasks with Sim to Real Transfer. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol.

5, no. 4, pp. 6724–6731, Oct. 2020. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.3015448.

S. Ambrogio, P. Narayanan, H. Tsai, R. M. Shelby, I. Boybat, C. di Nolfo, S. Sidler, M. Giordano, M. Bodini,

N. Farinha, **B. D. Killeen**, C. Cheng, Y. Jaoudi, G. W. Burr. Equivalent-accuracy accelerated neuralnetwork training using analogue memory. Nature, vol. 558, no. 7708, p. 60, Jun. 2018. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0180-5.

Peer-reviewed Conference Papers

C. Gao, X. Liu, W. Gu, **B. D. Killeen**, M. Armand, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Generalizing Spatial Transformers to Projective Geometry with Applications to 2D/3D Registrationc. MICCAI, 2020, arxiv:2003.10987.

X. Liu, Y. Zhang, B. Killeen, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Extremely Dense Point Correspondences using a Learned Feature Descriptor. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 4847-4856, 2020. J. Y. Wu\*, B. D. Killeen\*, P. Nikutta, M. Thies, A. Zapaishchykova, S. Chakraborty, M. Unberath. Changes M-2**Preprints** in Reproductive Rate of SARS-CoV-2 Due to Non-pharmaceutical Interventions in 1,417 U.S. Counties. medRxiv preprint, Jun. 2020, doi: 10.1101/2020.05.31.20118687. B. D. Killeen\*, J. Y. Wu\*, K. Shah, A. Zapaishchykova, P. Nikutta, A. Tamhane, S. Chakraborty, J. Wei, T. M - 1Gao, M. Thies, M. Unberath. A County-level Dataset for Informing the United States' Response to COVID-19. arXiv preprint, 2020, arXiv:2004.00756. G. W. Burr and **B. D. Killeen**. 2020. Efficient Processing of Convolutional Neural Network Layers Using Patents P-1 Analog-memory-based Hardware. 20200117986, filed March 25, 2019, and issued April 16, 2020, uspto.report/patent/app/20200117986. Teaching Assistant Teaching Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis, Department of Computer Science, University of 03/2019 - 06/2019 Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA With Prof. Yali Amit. Wrote supplementary course material and held weekly lab sessions. Selected review: "Ben was incredibly patient during office hours and always responsive to student questions. In addition, he often presented demos during office hours or showed easier ways to handle the homework assignments; both were very helpful." More reviews available at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2019-spring-lsda Grading Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA 01/2019 - 08/2019 - Scientific Visualization - Introduction to Computer Science I - Introduction to Computer Science II Tutoring Topics in Computer Science, Machine Learning, Baltimore, MD, USA. 06/2020 - present I tutor young people (middle- and high-school age) who are interested in CS and ML. More info at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2020-tutoring. Shreya Chakraborty, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2019 - present Supervision 12/2019 - 03/2020 Philipp Nikutta, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. Selected Coursework Graduate Theory of Computation Parallel Programming Nonlinear Optimization II Computer Integrated Surgery II Computer Integrated Surgery I Deep Learning Undergraduate Unsupervised Learning\* GPA: 3.81 Computer Vision Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis Operating Systems Honors Combinatorics Honors Algorithms Honors Discrete Mathematics Scientific Visualization Programming Languages Networks and Distributed Systems \*Graduate level. 2020 - present Memberships IEEE Graduate Student Member

Interests Creative nonfiction: benjamindkilleen.com/blog Science Fiction: novel available by request.

# Metadata

This document is available

- online: benjamindkilleen.com/markdown-cv.
- as a PDF: benjamindkilleen.com/files/cv.pdf.

Created based on markdown-cv by Eliseo Papa with styles based on David Whipp.

MIT License.

Last updated: October 2020